Guide to the Robert L. Patten: George Cruikshank research materials, 1792 - 2002, bulk 1836-1977 MS 493
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series III: Research photocopies and notes, 1810-2002, 235696; (27 boxes)
  - Sub-series D: Photocopies, 1812 - 1988, 235767
    - Stephens, Fred G., Essay on the Genius of George Cruikshank, notes, 235792 (Box 59, Folder 32)
    - Sterne, Laurence, Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, undated, 235791 (Box 59, Folder 33)
    - Sterrenburg, Lee, Psychoanalysis and the Iconography of Revolution, in Victorian Studies, 1975-76, 235790 (Box 59, Folder 34)
    - Stevenson, Lionel, The Showman of Vanity Fair: The Life of William Makepeace Thackery, 1947, 235789 (Box 59, Folder 35)
    - Sutherland, Guilland, Cruikshank and London, in Victorian Artists and the City, 1980, 235788 (Box 59, Folder 36)
    - Tegg, William, George Cruikshank, in Notes and Queries, notes, 235787 (Box 59, Folder 37)
    - Thackeray, William, George Cruikshank, in Westminster Review, 1840, 235786 (Box 59, Folder 38)
    - Thompson, Alice, A Bundle of Rue, in Magazine of Art, 1880, 235785 (Box 59, Folder 39)
    - Thornbury, Walter, British Artists from Hogarth to Turner, 1861, 235784 (Box 59, Folder 40)
    - Twyman, Michael, Lithography 1800-1850, 1970, 235783 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Veth, Cornelius, Comic Art in England, 1930, 235782 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Vizetelly, Henry, Glances Back Through Seventy Years, 1893, 235781 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Wakeman, Geoffrey, Victorian Book Illustration, 1973, 235780 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Ward, Mrs. E.M., Memories of Ninety Years, undated, 235779 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Wardroper, John, The Caricatures of George Cruikshank, review, 1978, 235778 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Wedmore, Frederick, Cruikshank, undated, 235777 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Weitenkampf, Frank, The Illustrated Book, 1938, 235776 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Wellesley Index to Victorian Periodicals, 1824-1900, notes, 235775 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - White, Gleeson, English Illustration, notes, 235774 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Work, Robert, R., Isaac Cruikshank's Drawings for Drolls, 1968, 235773 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - The Works of George Cruikshank, Victoria and Albert Museum, undated, 235772 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Worth, George J., William Harrison Ainsworth, notes, 235771 (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Wright, Thomas, Caricature History of the Georges, 1876, 235770 (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Wright, Thomas, A History of Caricature and Grotesque in Literature and Art, 1968, 235769 (Box 60, Folder 15)
    - Wynn-Jones, Michael, George Cruikshank: His Life and London, notes, 235768 (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Sub-series E: George Cruikshank research files, 1810-1992, 235742
    - Autographs and inscriptions, 1864, 1871, undated, 235766 (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Bates, William, bibliography on obituaries and letters from George Cruikshank to newspapers ( notes, photocopies), undated, 235765 (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - Biographies of George, Isaac and Robert Cruikshank, undated, 235764 (Box 60, Folder 19)
    - Biography, Joseph Jackson, Grunwald Center for Graphic Arts, UCLA (Preface - Chapter 14 ), circa 1939, 235763 (Box 60, Folder 20)
    - Biography, Joseph Jackson, Grunwald Center for Graphic Arts, UCLA (Chapter 15 - 25 ), circa 1939, 235762 (Box 60, Folder 21)
    - Cartoons, 1987-1992, 235761 (Box 60, Folder 22)
    - Collections, university, undated, 235760 (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
    - Contemporaries, undated, 235759 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Coutts accounts for George and Eliza Cruikshank, 1852-1892, 235758 (Box 61)
    - George Cruikshank: A Revaluation, index, undated, 235757 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Exhibitions, 1970-1974, undated, 235756 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Fragments, undated, 235755 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Genealogy, includes marriage and death certificates, 1978, 235754 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Letters (photocopies), circa 1853-1870, 235753 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Library of Congress checklist, British Political and Social Cartoons, 1655-1832, checklist 1968, 235752 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Materials listing by state, undated, 235751 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Obituary from The Art Journal, [1878], 235750 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Oil paintings, 1978 April 30, 235749 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Portraits, undated, 235748 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Private daybook, notes, 1810-1825, 235747 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Publisher's agreements, 1872, 235746 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - Residences, undated, 235745 (Box 62, Folder 13)
    - [Cruikshank's] sight, undated, 235744 (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified drawings, notes, 1982, 235743 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Sub-series F: Subject files, 1813 -1990, 235712
    - Altrie, Adelaide, 1988 July, 235741 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1986 July - September, 235740 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Axson Collection at Rice University, undated, 235739 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Book illustration, techniques, undated, 235738 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Browning, Logan, 1989 March - 1990 December, 235737 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Copyright, undated, 235736 (Box 63, Folder 6-8)
    - Cruikshank, Robert (photocopy, 1821, 1823), 235735 (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - Dickens, Charles, articles, 1813-1939, 235734 (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - Dickens, Charles, advertisements, 1858-1863, 235733 (Box 63, Folder 11)
    - Dickens, Charles, cartoons, 1976-1979, 235732 (Box 63, Folder 12)
    - Dickens, Charles, clippings, 1870-1964, 235731 (Box 63, Folder 13)
    - Dickens, Charles, illustrations, 1848, 235730 (Box 63, Folder 14)
    - Dickens, Charles, various works, 1873-1970, 235729 (Box 63, Folder 15)
    - The Drawing Society, 1988-1989, 235728 (Box 63, Folder 16)
    - Getty Foundation, 1984 October - 1986 May, 235727 (Box 63, Folder 17)
    - Glassman, Elizabeth, undated, 235726 (Box 63, Folder 18)
    - Humanities Research Center, Vermont, 1978, 235725 (Box 63, Folder 19)
    - Library of Congress, 1989, 235724 (Box 63, Folder 20)
    - Manchester research, 1934-1974, 235723 (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1986 February - 1988 December, 235722 (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - National Humanities Center, 1976-1988, 235721 (Box 63, Folder 23)
    - Places to visit (list of universities and other repositories), undated, 235720 (Box 63, Folder 24)
    - Research grants, 1978, 235719 (Box 63, Folder 25)
    - Robins, James, undated, 235718 (Box 63, Folder 26)
    - Rowlandson exhibition, 1978, 235717 (Box 63, Folder 27)
    - Soundings program, 1988, 235716 (Box 63, Folder 28)
    - Texas Committee for the Humanities, 1987-1988, 235715 (Box 63, Folder 29)
    - Thackery, William Makepeace, 1946-1947, 235714 (Box 63, Folder 30)
    - Times Literary Supplement, 1974, 235713 (Box 63, Folder 31)
  - Sub-series G: Lectures, Robert Patten, 1973-1989, undated, 235699
    - George Cruikshank, Friends of the Library, 1973, 235711 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - The Rise and Fall of the Leaf: Representing Culture in England, 1815-1845, INCS Conference, 1987 April, 235710 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Response to Huxley and the Popularization of Science, Rice University, 1987 September, 235709 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - The Culture of Caricature, National Humanities Center, 1988 March 2, 235708 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - From Regency Caricature to Victorian Fiction, UNC, 1988 April 6, 235707 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Counting Change: From Beggar to Threepenny, Ackland Art Museum, 1988 April 13, 235706 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Imaging the City: Charles Dickens and Geroge Cruikshank, J.B. Speed Art Museum, 1988 October 13, 235705 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Bah! Humbug!, American Association of University Women, Chapel Hill, NC, 1988 December 3, 235704 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - George Cruikshank's Urban Eye, Indiana University, 1989 January 19, 235703 (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Just Say No: Temperance Propaganda in Victorian Britain, Peace College, 1989 March 20, 235702 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Dickens by the Numbers, Greenville, SC, 1989 April, 235701 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Mellon Center, Rowlandson College, undated, 235700 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Sub-series H: Oversize materials, 1823-1981, 235697
    - Photocopies of newspaper articles, reviews, and prints. Also includes a folder with illustrations and articles on the characteristics of coloring of prints of this period., 235698 (Box 65)
- Series IV: Prints, pamphlets, illustrations, paintings and plates, 1807-1988, 235387; (17 boxes)
  - This series includes prints, pamphlets and illustrations including etchings, engravings and woodcuts. Many are single leaves or a series of leaves from books illustrated by Cruikshank, others are bound or loosely bound books and pamphlets. Still others are proofs (some mounted) on India paper. These prints are arranged by title of publication or title of individual print if the publication is unknown. Prints by Isaac, Robert and Percy Cruikshank are included in the series., 235695
  - Sub-series A: Illustrations for books, pamphlets, tracts and periodicals, 1815-1903., 235544
    - Arranged alphabetically by title of publication or print. The author's name is indicated in paranthesis if known. The corresponding Cohn number is included at the end of each entry if applicable., 235694
    - Abraham Thornton. Tried for the Murder of Mary Ashford, 1819, 235693 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Arthur O'Leary (Charles Lever), 10 etchings, 1845, Cohn 183-184, 235692 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Aunt Judy's Christmas Volume for Young People (Mrs. Gatty), 2 plates, Amelia and the Dwarfs, and Benjy in Beastland, 1870, Cohn 346, 235691 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - The Bands in the Park, pamphlet with woodcut illustrations, 4 pages, 1856, Cohn 206, 235690 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Barney Buntline and Billy Bowling (George Coleman), words and music, etching on title page, uncolored, undated, Cohn 152, 235689 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - The Bee and the Wasp, 4 proofs on India paper, 1832, Cohn 65, 235688 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Bentley's Miscellany, 1837 January 2, Cohn 69, 235687 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Bentley's Miscellany, 33 plates, 1837-1841, Cohn 69, 235686 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Bentley's Miscellany, 18 plates, 1837-1841, Cohn 69, 235685 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Bentley's Miscellany, Reports of the Second Meeting of the Mudfrog Association, The Tyrant Songster, 1838, Cohn 66, 235684 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Bentley's Miscellany, Vincent Eden, The Proctor at Home. A Visitation and a Visit, 1839, Cohn 66, 235683 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Bentley's Miscellany, 1847 July 1, 235682 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - The Betting Book, pamphlet with 5 woodcuts, 1852, Cohn 201, 235681 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - The Biglow Papers (J.R. Lowell), 1861, Cohn 518, 235680 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - The Brighton Lodging House (Francis Higginson), 2 etchings, The Sycophant Assailed, and The Witch, 1849, Cohn 388, 235679 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - The British Journal, woodcut on wrapper, 1852, Cohn 91, 235678 (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - Catholic Miracles, 7 woodcuts on 4 leaves, Cohn 122, 235677 (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Chemistry, No Mystery; or a Lecturer's Bequest… (John Scoffern), woodcut frontispiece, Laughing Gas, and title, 1839, Cohn 728, 235676 (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Clement Lorimer (Angus B. Reach), 4 etchings, Part II: The Wreck, and Making the Favorite Safe, Part IV: Benosa at the Tomb and Part V: Making Circumstantial Evidence, 1849, Cohn 687, 235675 (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1835-1838, incomplete, Cohn 184, 235674 (Box 66, Folder 20)
    - The Comic Almanack, title page, first series, 1835-1843, 235673 (Box 66, Folder 21)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1835, 235672 (Box 66, Folder 22)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1836, 235671 (Box 66, Folder 23)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1837, 235670 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1838, 235669 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1839, 235668 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1840, 235667 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1841, 235666 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1842, 235665 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1843, 235664 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1844, 235663 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1845, 235662 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1846, 235661 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1847, 235660 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1848, 235659 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1849, 235658 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1849, 235657 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1850, 235656 (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1851, 235655 (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - The Comic Almanack, 1852, 235654 (Box 67, Folder 17)
    - The Comic Offering, 1 woodcut, Falstaff in the Basket, 1833, Cohn 154, 235653 (Box 67, Folder 18)
    - Dibdin's Songs, cover, 1863, 235652 (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Six Illustrations to Cowpers Diverting History of John Gilpin, by George Cruikshank, 5 proofs on India paper, 1828, Cohn 169, 235651 (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Don Quixote (Roscoe's Novelists Library), 1833, Cohn 710, 235650 (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - The Epping Hunt (Thomas Hood), 6 proofs on India paper, 1829, Cohn 406, 235649 (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - The Everyday Book, or Everlasting Calendar of Popular Amusements… (William Hone), 6 woodcuts (columns 47, 903, 1114, 1322, 1431 and column 50 in Vol.II), 1826, Cohn 402, 235648 (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - Factiae and Miscellanies. With one hundred and twenty engravings by George Cruikshank (William Hone), 2nd edition, 1827, Cohn 405, 235647 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Fairy Library, I: Hop o' of My Thumb and the Seven League Boots, 6 etchings, 1853, Cohn 196, 235646 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Fairy Library, II: The History of Jack and the Beanstalk, 6 etchings, 1854. Cohn 197, 235645 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Fairy Library, III: Cinderella and the Glass Slipper, 10 etchings, 1854, Cohn 198, 235644 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Fairy Library, IV: Puss in Boots, 1864, 235643 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Fairy Library, 1 volume, covers loose, missing, 1885, 235642 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Fairy Library, 1 volume, covers missing, 1885, 235641 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - The Fairy Mythology (Thomas Keightley), etched frontispiece, 1850, Cohn 458, 235640 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - The Fatal Boots and Cox's Diary (William Thackeray), undated, 235639 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Frank Fairlegh (Frank Smedley), 30 illustrations, 2 sets, 1850, Cohn 754, 235638 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - George Cruikshank's Magazine, 3 etchings, Tobacco Leaves No. 1, Elephantine Performances, and Trying to Cure a Bear of a Sore Head, 1854, Cohn 185, 235637 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - George Cruikshank's Omnibus, Commentary upon the 'New Police Act' no.2, 1841, Cohn 190, 235636 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - George Cruikshank's Omnibus, p. 1-130, 1841-1842, Cohn 190, 235635 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - George Cruikshank's Omnibus, p. 1-144; 177-300, 1841-1842, Cohn 190, 235634 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - George Cruikshank's Omnibus, no. III, p. 65-96, 1841-1842, Cohn 190, 235633 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - George Cruikshank's Omnibus, 1841-1842, Cohn 190, 235632 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - George Cruikshank's Omnibus, 1841-1842, Cohn 190, 235631 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - George Cruikshank's Omnibus, 1842, Cohn 190, 235630 (Box 69)
    - German Popular Stories (Brothers Grimm), 1823, Cohn 369, 235629 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Giles Chawbacon (see also Bentley's Miscellany), circa 1840, 235628 (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - The Gin Shop (Illustrated Penny Readings, J.W. Kirton), 13 woodcuts, 16 p., [1869], Cohn 468, 235627 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - The Glass and the New Crystal Palace, pamphlet, 11 woodcuts, 1853, Cohn 203, 235626 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - The History of Napoleon Bonaparte, 4 woodcuts by George Cruikshank (includes engravings by others), 1829, Cohn 589, 235625 (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - The History of the French Revolution, wrapper with design by George Cruikshank, 1838, Cohn 793, 235624 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - History of the Irish Rebellion in 1798 (W.H. Maxwell), 2 etchings, The Rebels executing their Prisoners on the Bridge at Wexford, and Massacre at Scullabogue, 1845, Cohn 541, 235623 (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Hogarth Moralized, 4 designs on 2 plates, 1831, Cohn 397, 235622 (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - The Holiday Grammar (Alfred Crowquill), 1825, 235621 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Holiday Scenes, 4 etchings, uncolored, 1826, 235620 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - The Humourist, etching, Tit for Tat, or the Officer and his Irish Servant, 1820, Cohn 419, 235619 (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Illustrated Magazine of Art, woodcut design after George Cruikshank (Williams sculp), 1853, Cohn 427, 235618 (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - Italian Tales, Tales of Humor, Gallantry and Romanc, woodcuts, proofs, 1824, Cohn 444, 235617 (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - John Manasty (Maginn), 6 etchings, 1844, Cohn 523, 235616 (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - Land and Sea Tales (M.H. Barker), 4 etchings, 2 frontispieces and 2 vignette titles, 1836, Cohn 56, 235615 (Box 69, Folder 23)
    - Life in London (Pierce Egan), 22 colored etchings by I.R. and G. Cruikshank, 1821, Cohn 262, 235614 (Box 69, Folder 24)
    - Life in Paris (David Carey), wrapper, 1822, Cohn 109, 235613 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Life of Napoleon, 1815, 235612 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Life of Sir John Falstaff, (R.B. Brough), 3 full-page etchings, 1857-1858, Cohn 96, 235611 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - London Characters, Watchman, 1829, Cohn 182, 235610 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - London Society, full page woodcut after George Cruikshank, "I marry, " said Jack, "The man is mad. I don't want to marry!" 1864, Cohn 502, 235609 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Lorimer Littlegood, (A.W. Cole), 12 plates by Cruikshank, 1858, Cohn 148, 235608 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Lorimer Littlegood, (A.W. Cole), 12 plates, 1858, Cohn 148, 235607 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Lucien Grenville, (T.J. Pettigrew), 5 proofs, 1833, Cohn 645, 235606 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Illustrated Magazine of Art, wrapper, 1853, Cohn 427, 235605 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - The Man in the Moon, pamphlet, 1820, Cohn 527, 235604 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Memoirs of Joseph Grimaldi, (Charles Dickens), 6 etchings, 1838, Cohn 237, 235603 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Memoirs of Joseph Grimaldi, (Charles Dickens), portrait of Grimaldi and 12 etchings, 1846, 1848, 1854, Cohn 237, 235602 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Memoirs of Robert William Elliston, comedian (George Raymond), 3 etchings by George Cruikshank, portrait by Harlowe, 1844-1845, Cohn 686, 235601 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Memoirs of the Life and Writing of Lord Byron (George Clinton), woodcut plates after George Cruikshank, 1825, Cohn, 235600 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Midnight Scenes and Social Photographs, etched frontispiece, 1858, Cohn 557, 235599 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - The Miraculous Host, 1822,. woodcuts, Cohn 562, 235598 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Monsieur Tonson (John Taylor), 1830, 7 proofs on India paper, Cohn 783, 235597 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Mornings at Bow Street (J. Wight), 1st edition, 2nd issue, text, 1824, Cohn 844, 235596 (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Mornings at Bow Street (J. Wight), 1st edition, 2nd issue, illustrations and title page, 1824, Cohn 844, 235595 (Box 70, Folder 19)
    - New Year's Day: A Winter's Tale (Mrs. Gore), 4 etchings, [1864] Cohn 357, 235594 (Box 70, Folder 20)
    - The Non Mi Ricordo, pamphlet with three woodcuts, 1820, Cohn 606, 235593 (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - The Novels of Henry Fielding, 20 etchings on steel, undated, 235592 (Box 70, Folder 22)
    - Old Miscellany Days: A Selection of Stories from Bentley's Miscellany, 1885, 235591 (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - Our Own Times, etchings, "An Outline of Society in Our Own Times," "Almanacks - Over the Water," "The Ragged School," "Tremendous Sacrifice," other illustrations in this set, not part of "Our Own Times," but appeared to have been bound together, 1846, Cohn 193, 235590 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Our Own Times, part I, with wrapper, etchings, woodcuts and glyphographs, 1846, Cohn 193, 235589 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Our Own Times, The Ragged School, 1846, 235588 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - A Penny Political Picture for the People, etching, The British Beehive, 1867, Cohn 634, 235587 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - The Pentamerone or The Story of Stories, etchings, (G. Basile), 1848, Cohn 60, 235586 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Peter Parley's Annual, woodcuts, 1840, Cohn 641, 235585 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Peter Schlemial, etchings, Cohn 475, 235584 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Pilgrim's Progress (Bunyan), drawings on wood, 1816, 1903, Cohn 100, 235583 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Points of Humour, Part I, 4 etchings, 1823, Cohn 176, 235582 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Points of Humour, proofs, 1823-1824, Cohn 176, 235581 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - The Political "A, Apple-Pie," or The Extraordinary Red Book, pamphlet, 1820, Cohn 659, 235580 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - The Political House that Jack Built, pamphlet, 1819, Cohn 663, 235579 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - The Political Showman-at Home, pamphlet, 1821, Cohn 668, 235578 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - The Power of Conscience, etched frontispiece and vignette, 1815, Cohn 672, 235577 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - A Present for an Apprentice, etched frontispiece and title page, 1838, Cohn 673, 235576 (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Prisons and Prisoners (Adshead), etched frontispiece "Newgate - Prison Discipline," 1845, Cohn 6, 235575 (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Punch and Judy (J.P. Collier), etchings and woodcuts, 1828, Cohn 150, 235574 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Puss in Boots, 1864 (Box 71)
    - The Queen's Matrimonial Ladder, 1820, pamphlet with toy ladder, woodcuts, Cohn 680, 235573 (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - The Queen's Matrimonial Ladder, pamphlet, 1820, Cohn 680, 235572 (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - Rejected Addresses (H. and J. Smith), 4 proofs, woodcuts, 1833, Cohn 759, 235571 (Box 71, Folder 20)
    - Roscoe's edition of Smollett's Works, etchings and a portrait engraved by Freeman, 1831, Cohn 702, 235570 (Box 71, Folder 22)
    - Roscoe's Novelist's Library, "Amelia," "Tom Jones, " and "Don Quixote," 1831-1833, Cohn 701-711, 235569 (Box 71, Folder 23)
    - Roscoe's Novelist's Library, The Expedition of Humphrey Clinker, 1831, Cohn 702, 235568 (Box 71, Folder 24)
    - Roscoe's Novelist's Library, The History of Tom Jones, 1831, Cohn 705, 235567 (Box 71, Folder 25)
    - The Slap at the Shop, "with twenty-seven cuts," 1822, Cohn 749, 235566 (Box 71, Folder 26)
    - A Slice of Bread and Butter, pamphlet, woodcuts, 1870, Cohn 207, 235565 (Box 71, Folder 27)
    - Smiles for All Seasons, etched frontispeice, 1825, Cohn 756, 235564 (Box 71, Folder 28)
    - The Snow Storm (Mrs. C.F. Gore), 3 etchings, 1845, 235563 (Box 71, Folder 29)
    - The Songster's Multumin Parvo, 4 engravings, undated, Cohn 763, 235562 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Specimens of German Romance (G. Soane), 3 etched frontispieces, 1826, Cohn 760, 235561 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - The Spirit of Public Journals, 1826, Cohn 769, 235560 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Stanley Thorn (H. Cockton), 1841, Cohn 147, 235559 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Sunday in London (J. Wight), 11 woodcuts, vignettes, 1833, Cohn 846, 235558 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Table Book, proofs and etchings, 1845, Cohn 191, 235557 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Table Book, 12 etchings and title page, 1845, Cohn 191, 235556 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Three Courses and a Dessert (William Clarke), 3 woodcuts, 1860, Cohn 144, 235555 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Top-Sail Sheet Blocks (M.H. Barker), etched frontispeice, 1838, Cohn 57, 235554 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Tough Yarns (M.H. Barker), 9 woodcuts, 1835, Cohn 55, 235553 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Uncle Tom's Cabin (Harriet Beecher Stowe), illustrations on wood, 1852, Cohn 777, 235552 (Box 72, Folder 11)